Anita Weschler Papers
Anita Weschler Papers
1898-1991
Weschler, Anita.
51 linear ft.
Papers of the American sculptor, painter, interior decorator, poet, author. Collection includes correspondence, artwork (sketches, watercolors), exhibition catalogs, photographs, writings, and memorabilia, including financial material.
148748
Biographical History
Anita Weschler (1903-2000) was an American sculptor, painter, interior decorator, poet, and author. Born in New York, the daughter of J. Charles and Hulda Mayer Weschler, she studied in New York City at the Horace Mann School and studied art at the Parsons School of Design, the Art Students League under William Zorach and the Pennsylvania Academy of Fine Arts with Albert Laessle. In 1928 she married Herbert E. Solomon and most of her career was spent at Long Hill, their home/studio in Erwinna, Bucks County, Pennsylvania. She also kept an apartment in New York and in the early 1980's, after selling Long Hill, she relocated there permanently.
Weschler's sculpture has been exhibited at the Metropolitan Museum of Art, the Museum of Modern Art, the Chicago Art Institute, the Pennsylvania Academy of Art, the Carnegie Institute of Art, the Whitney Museum of American Art and other museums and galleries throughout the United States. Her work is represented in permanent collections of the Whitney Museum, the Norfolk Museum and many others as well as in private collections. She has had fourteen one man shows, five one man travelling shows and has been represented in ten group travelling shows. Her translucencies, paintings in fibre glass, were exhibited at the Wellons Gallery in 1956. She was a member of the Bucks County Art Alliance and the National Association of Women Artists; like many of her fellow artists, she also worked with the government's Federal Arts Project during the Depression (one example of her work is a terra cotta relief created for the Post Office in Elkin, NC).
Awards to Weschler include commissions for sculpture from the United States Post Office, and prizes at the Corcoran Gallery, San Francisco Museum and the American Federation of Arts Travelling Show. She has been a fellow at the MacDowell Colony, Peterboro, New Hampshire, and the Yaddo Foundation, Saratoga Springs, New York. Weschler is a member of the Architectural League, Sculptor's Guild, National Association of Women Artists and Federation of Modern Painters and Sculptors.
Articles by Weschler have appeared in various art magazines and she is the author of a book of poetry, Nightshade.
One of her more well-known pieces, and one of the first-ever sculptural uses of fiberglass, is The Humanist, composed of fiberglass, bonded bronze and plastic resins. The Humanist, a standing figure with outstretched hands embodying the ideal secular humanist, was exhibited at the Guggenheim's outdoor sculpture garden in 1955 and eventually became the property of noted activist, writer and humanist Warren Allen Smith. Smith donated the sculpture to the Institute for Humanist Studies (IHS) in 2005, and it now graces the entrance of IHS headquarters in Albany, New York.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Anita Weschler Papers consists of appointment books, art organizations, artwork, correspondence, exhibit catalogs, financial records, memorabilia, photographs, printed material, and writings.
Appointment books cover nearly 40 years of the artist's working and personal life.
Art organizations files contain material relating to various art galleries, guilds, artists colonies, and schools, including the Archives of American Art, the Art Students League, the MacDowell Colony, and the Sculptors Guild.
Artwork includes original sketches for costumes and fashions, for designs and interior designs, sketches in crayon, ink and pencil, prints, and water colors. Sketchbooks are at the end of this series.
Correspondence is largely incoming from friends, family, admirers, writers, artists and museums.Correspondence pertaining to specific interior decorating jobs is included with the interior decorating material in the Financial records series (see below). Significant correspondents include artists (Doris Caesar), galleries (Mortimer-Levitt Gallery), museums (Columbia Museum of Art, Metropolitan Museum of Art), organizations (Artists' Equity Foundation, Sculptor's Guild, Yaddo Foundation), and writers (Padraic Colum, Chaim Gross, Thornton Wilder).
A partial index to correspondence is provided at the end of this finding aid. However, this index is NOT comprehensive. It covers only the [General] correspondence in Boxes 22-34. It does not include Business or Personal correspondence in Boxes 8-22.
Exhibit catalogues include Anita Weschler one man shows, Anita Weschler shows with other artists, and shows of other artists, arranged chronologically within each category.
Financial records include bank books, bank statements, bills and receipts, checkbooks, expenses and budgets, income taxes, insurance policies, interior decorating job files for various clients, and legal documents.
Memorabilia includes addresses and mailing lists, awards, autographs, biographical material, book lists, business cards, brochures on art equipment and techniques, exhibition schedules, clippings about friends, a guest book, and prints arranged in that order. Also included is material about the various art organizations with which Weschler was associated and a diary kept by Weschler's mother.
Photographs include photographs of Weschler, her family, friends and travels.
Printed material contains exhibit material, issues of various periodicals including Playbill magazine, programs from various performances, and miscellaneous items.
Recordings contains audiorecordings of interviews of Weschler and others, as well as Weschler reminiscing on her life and work.
Writings include handwritten and typescript manuscripts of articles, book reviews, books, diaries, essays, lectures, notebooks, notes, plays, poems, press releases, radio interviews, radio talks, short stories and untitled short pieces. Also included here are a few writings by others: Carl Carmer, Joseph Hudnut, Louise Lamprey and J. Charles Weschler.
Arrangement of the Collection
Appointment books and Correspondence are arranged chronologically. Undated correspondence, arranged alphabetically, follows the chronologically arranged letters. Incoming letters to members of Weschler's family are at the end of the correspondence, alphabetically arranged by recipient's name. Exhibit catalogs are alphabetical by type of show, and within that chronologically.
Art organizations are arranged alphabetically by name of organization. Artwork, Financial records, Memorabilia, and Printed material are arranged alphabetically by type. Photographs are arranged alphabetically by subject. Writings are arranged alphabetically by type, and within each type alphabetically by title. Writings by others are filed at the end of this series.
Separated Material
One book has been transferred to Rare Books for cataloging. It is indicated in the inventory below.
Subject and Genre Headings
Art -- Sculptors; Art -- Painters; Benét, William Rose, 1886-1950.; Boswell, Peyton, 1904-1950.; Brian, Doris.; Burle Marx, Roberto, 1909-1994.; Colum, Padraic, 1881-1972.; Cuthbert, Clifton, 1907-1978.; Fillmore, Parker Hoystead, 1878-; Freydberg, Ralph M.; Frost, Frances, 1905-1959.; Glowacki, Michaline.; Golden, Trudy.; Gorelik, Frances.; Graham, French W.; Grandin, Ruth.; Greenbaum, Beatrice.; Heine, Irwin Millard.; Hellinger, Joshua, 1907-1960.; Hopper, Inslee A.; Hudnut, Joseph, 1886-1968.; Humphrey, Doris, 1895-1958.; Hunn, Marianne.; Jenni, Donald, 1937-2006.; Jonas, Louis Paul, 1894-1971.; Kallock, Almansor.; Katzenberg, Elva S.; Koestler, Elsa Weschler.; Korff, Betty Hurd.; Lamprey, Louise, 1869-1951.; Langfeld, Beatrice.; Lewenthal, Reeves.; Limón, José; MacDowell, Marian.; Marceau, Henri, 1896-1969.; Mayer, Sophie.; McNickle, D'Arcy.; Montague, Ward.; Pearce, Glenn.; Piper, Raymond Frank.; Read, Gardner, 1913-2005.; Rewald, Estelle.; Richardson, Nina Maud.; Robinson, George S.; Rowan, Edward Beatty, 1898-1946.; Schlick, Frederick.; Smith, Warren Allen, 1921-; Solomon, Herbert E.; Sommerich, Jane.; Spencer, James Houston.; Ulreich, Bukannura.; Vitarelli, V.; Weschler, Adolphus.; Weschler, Anita.; Weschler, Hulda Mayer.; Weschler, J. Charles.; Wescott, Glenway, 1901-1987.; Wescott, Paul, 1904-1970.; Whiting, Frederic Allen.; Whitney, Parkhurst.; Willets, Eliza L.; Zorach, Marguerite, 1887-1968.; Zorach, William, 1887-1966.; American Artists Group.; American Federation of Arts.; Architectural League of New York.; Art Students League (New York, N.Y.); Artists Equity Association.; New York Enthusiasts.; Sculptors Guild (New York, N.Y.); Art, American -- 20th century.; Interior decorators -- United States.; Jews, American.; Painters -- United States.; Painting, Modern -- 20th century.; Sculptors -- United States.; Sculpture, American.; Sculpture, Modern -- 20th century.; Women artists -- United States.; Women painters -- United States.; Women poets -- United States.; Women poets, American.; Women sculptors -- United States.; Appointment books.; Articles.; Audiocassettes.; Sound recordings.; Awards.; Bank statements.; Bankbooks.; Calendars (documents); Clippings (information artifacts); Correspondence.; Diaries.; Exhibition catalogs.; Interviews.; Manuscripts for publication.; Notebooks.; Photographs.; Poems.; Receipts (financial records); Sketches.; Slides (photographs); Artists.; Interior decorators.; Painters.; Poets.; Sculptors.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Anita Weschler, 1965-2001.
Inventory
- Appointment books
  - Appointment books, 1921; 1923 (Box 1)
  - Appointment books, 1929-1939; 5 folders (Box 1)
  - Appointment books, 1940-1959; 9 folders (Box 2)
- Art organizations
  - American Crafts Council (Box 2)
  - The Architectural League of New York (Box 2)
  - Archives of American Art (Box 2)
  - Art Students League (Box 2)
  - Artist-Craftsmen of New York (Box 3)
  - Arts Alliance of Bucks County (Box 3)
  - Bucks County Council for the Arts (Box 3)
  - Daniel Lewis Dance Repertory Company (Box 3)
  - Delaware Valley Artists Association (Box 3)
  - Federation of Modern Painters and Sculptors, Inc. (Box 3)
  - The Fine Arts Federation of New York (Box 3)
  - International Association of Art, Inc. (IAA) (Box 3)
  - The MacDowell Colony (Box 3)
  - Mother Joseph Foundation (Box 3)
  - National Association of Women Artists, Inc. (Box 3)
  - Pennsylvania Academy of the Fine Arts (Box 3)
  - Phillips Mill Community Association (Box 3)
  - Sculptors Guild, Inc. (Box 3)
  - Sculptors Guild, Inc. (Box 4)
  - Miscellaneous, 2 folders (Box 4)
- Artwork
  - List and price lists (Box 4)
  - Charcoal drawings, 12 items (Oversize 1)
  - Collage (probably child's) (Oversize 2)
  - Oil painting (Oversize 2)
  - Prints (Box 4)
  - Sculpture
    - Photographs, 2 folders (Box 4)
    - Cassette and slides, George and Gladys Robinson
      - George and Gladys Robinson interviewed, on sculpture, Limited Edition, weschler_a_014; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 53)
      - Slides, 20 items (Box 4)
    - Materials (Box 4)
    - Materials (Box 5)
    - "Techniques and Opinions" (Box 5)
    - "Techniques and Opinions" notebooks, 4 folders (Box 5)
    - "Techniques and Opinions" notebooks, 3 folders (Box 6)
  - Sketches
    - Costumes and fashions, pencil, pen, watercolor, 2 folders (Box 6)
    - Costumes and fashions, ink, pencil, watercolor, 36 items (Oversize 3)
    - Designs, pencil, watercolor (Box 6)
    - Crayon (Oversize 4)
    - Crayon, pencil, charcoal, 1925-1929; 81 items (Oversize 2)
    - Ink (Box 6)
    - Interior design, pencil (Box 6)
    - Pencil, Mrs. Marian MacDowell, Dec 1944 (Box 6)
    - Pencil, Mrs. Marian MacDowell, Dec 1944 (Oversize 2)
    - Pencil sketches for Human Events series, 1945; 10 items (Oversize 1)
  - Sketchbooks
    - Museum sketches (Box 7)
    - Sketch books, 13 volumes in 8 folders (Box 7)
    - Sketch books, 2 volumes (Box 8)
    - Sketch books, 3 volumes (Oversize 7)
    - Sketch books (Oversize 5)
    - Sketch books, 4 volumes; including notes and sketches in pencil, crayon, charcoal (Oversize 6)
  - Statuette fragment (Oversize 4)
  - Watercolors (Box 8)
  - Artwork by Herbert Solomon, 1919; mechanical drawings; 17 items (Oversize 2)
  - Artwork by Paul Wescott (Box 8)
- Correspondence
  A partial index to correspondence is provided at the end of this finding aid. However, this index is NOT comprehensive. It covers only the [General] correspondence in Boxes 22-34. It does not include Business or Personal correspondence in Boxes 8-22.
  See also Financial records: Interior decorating job files.
  - Business, 1926-1966; 4 folders (Box 8)
  - Business, 1967-1972; 5 folders (Box 9)
  - Business, 1973-1979; 7 folders (Box 10)
  - Business, 1980-1991; 2 folders (Box 11)
  - Business, undated; 2 folders (Box 11)
  - Christmas cards, 1948-1961; 2 folders (Box 11)
  - Christmas cards, 1962-1967; 4 folders (Box 12)
  - Christmas cards, 1968-1974; 5 folders (Box 13)
  - Christmas cards, 1975-1986; 1988-1989; 5 folders (Box 14)
  - Christmas cards, undated; 4 folders (Box 15)
  - Birthday cards (Box 15)
  - Personal, 1924; 1928,; 1932,; 1947,; 1952-1959; 2 folders (Box 15)
  - Personal, 1960-1964; 5 folders (Box 16)
  - Personal, 1964-1967; 5 folders (Box 17)
  - Personal, 1968-1970; 5 folders (Box 18)
  - Personal, 1971-1972; 2 folders (Box 19)
  - Personal, 1973-1976; 4 folders (Box 20)
  - Personal, 1977-1985; 9 folders (Box 21)
  - Personal, 1986-1989; 4 folders (Box 22)
  - Personal, undated; 3 folders (Box 22)
  - [General], 1903; 1905,; 1907,; 1913,; 1920-1922; 2 folders (Box 22)
  - [General], 1923-1926; 7 folders (Box 23)
  - [General], 1927-1932; 8 folders (Box 24)
  - [General], 1933-1937 Feb; 8 folders (Box 25)
  - [General], 1937 Feb-1939 Jun; 7 folders (Box 26)
  - [General], 1939 Jul-1942; 6 folders (Box 27)
  - [General], 1943-1946; 6 folders (Box 28)
  - [General], 1947-July 1950; 8 folders (Box 29)
  - [General], Oct Aug 1950-June 1953; 7 folders (Box 30)
  - [General], July 1953-Aug 1955; 6 folders (Box 31)
  - [General], Sep 1955-Dec 1957; 6 folders (Box 32)
  - [General], Dec 1957-1960; 7 folders (Box 33)
  - A-F, undated; 4 folders (Box 33)
  - G-Z, undated; 12 folders (Box 34)
  - Unidentified, undated (Box 34)
  - Correspondence of others
    - Koestler, Elsa Weschler, 1922-1948 (Box 34)
    - Limon, Jose, 1948 (Box 34)
    - Mayer, Sophie, 1902 (Box 34)
    - Solomon, Herbert, 1943-1959 (Box 34)
    - Weschler, Hulda Mayer, 1902-1923 (Box 34)
    - Weschler, J. Charles, 1906-1952 (Box 34)
- Exhibition catalogues
  - One man shows, A. Weschler, 1937-1978 (Box 34)
  - A. Weschler with others, 1932-1935 (Box 34)
  - A. Weschler with others, 1936-1960; 11 folders (Box 35)
  - A. Weschler with others, 1962-1984; 2 folders (Box 36)
  - A. Weschler with others, undated (Box 36)
  - Other artists, 1919; 1925-1935; 4 folders (Box 36)
  - Other artists, 1937-1974; 6 folders (Box 37)
  - Other artists, 1976; 1979,; 1981-1982,; 1985,; undated (Box 38)
- Financial records
  - Bank books, 1926-1945 (Box 38)
  - Bank loans and receipts, 1934-1952 (Box 38)
  - Bank statements, 1930-1933; 3 folders (Box 38)
  - Bank statements, 1933-1939; 6 folders (Box 39)
  - Bank statements, 1940-1947; 7 folders (Box 40)
  - Bank statements, 1948-1956; 8 folders (Box 41)
  - Bank statements, 1957-1962; 6 folders (Box 42)
  - Bank statements, 1963-1964; 1968; 2 folders (Box 43)
  - Bills and receipts, 1926-1945; 4 folders (Box 43)
  - Bills and receipts, 1946-1961; 7 folders (Box 44)
  - Bills and receipts, 1962-1973; 6 folders (Box 45)
  - Bills and receipts, undated; 4 folders (Box 46)
  - Budgets (Box 46)
  - Checkbooks, 1926-1927 (Box 46)
  - Checkbooks, 1929-1945; 5 folders (Box 47)
    Items dated 1929-1936 have inactive black mold
  - Checkbooks, 1946-1953; 4 folders (Box 48)
  - Checkbooks, 1953-1959; 3 folders (Box 49)
  - Checkbooks, 1954-1962; 4 folders (Box 49)
  - Checkbooks, 1963-1964 (Box 50)
  - Delivery receipts, 1954-1976 (Box 50)
  - Expenses and budgets, 1941-1955 (Box 50)
  - Income taxes, undated (Box 50)
  - Insurance policies, 1939-1957 (Box 50)
  - Insurance, 2 folders (Box 50)
  - Interior decorating job files
    - Genis, Mrs. S., 1929-1930; correspondence (Box 50)
    - Gettner, Mrs. Heiman, 1934; correspondence (Box 50)
    - Gilbert, Olive, 1931-1932; correspondence (Box 50)
    - Gottesman, Olive, 1928-1929 (Box 50)
    - Grande, Mrs. Victor, 1930; correspondence (Box 50)
    - Kalvin, Mrs. A., 1930; correspondence (Box 50)
    - Kaufman, Mrs. B.J., 1930; correspondence (Box 51)
    - Koestler, Mrs. Melvin, 1930; correspondence (Box 51)
    - Merman, Mrs. Mildred, 1936-1937; correspondence (Box 51)
    - Newmark, Mr. Charles, 1936; correspondence (Box 51)
    - Pell, Mrs. Hamilton, 1931-1953; correspondence (Box 51)
    - Portnow, Mrs. Henry, 1939-1940; correspondence (Box 51)
    - Howard S. Redell & Co., 1953; correspondence (Box 51)
    - Robinson, George, 1953; correspondence (Box 51)
    - Rogers, Mrs. John Jr., 1937-1938 (Box 51)
    - Schoffer, Max, 1929; correspondence (Box 51)
    - Schatzkin, Mrs. Henry, 1932; correspondence (Box 51)
    - Shire, Mildred, 1933-1935 (Box 51)
    - Sidney Ross Gallery, 1932 (Box 51)
    - Solomon, Herbert and Mrs., 1928; correspondence (Box 51)
    - Somper, Ruth, 1929-1935; correspondence (Box 52)
    - Steele, Emma, 1929-1935; correspondence (Box 52)
    - Zuckerman, Mrs. Robert, 1930 (Box 52)
    - Credit slips, 1930-1931 (Box 52)
    - Miscellaneous receipts, 1930-1931 (Box 52)
  - Lease information (Box 52)
  - Legal documents, 1925-1936; bond, deed, contract (Box 52)
  - Legal, miscellaneous (Box 52)
  - Moving and delivery receipts (Box 53)
  - Receipts
    - Art supplies (Box 53)
    - Auction purchases (Box 53)
    - Con Edison (Box 53)
    - Credit cards, 2 folders (Box 53)
    - IFC of New York (Box 53)
    - Membership dues (Box 53)
    - Telephone (Box 53)
    - Miscellaneous, 2 folders (Box 53)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 53)
- Memorabilia
  - Addresses, mailing lists, 4 folders (Box 53)
  - Addresses, mailing lists, 3 folders (Box 54)
  - Artists Equity Association, 1952-1954; by-laws, minutes, memos, membership (Box 54)
  - Artists for Victory Incorporated, 1942; minutes, finances (Box 54)
  - Autographs, George Arliss, Julia Marlowe, Eugene O'Neill (Box 54)
  - Awards, 1918; 1955 (Box 54)
  - Biographical material
    - Biographical data and publicity, 1950s-1960s; 2 folders (Box 54)
    - Biographical data and publicity, 1970s; undated; 3 folders (Box 55)
    - Baby's record, 1903-1904 (Box 55)
    - The Horace Mann School class book, 1922 (Box 55)
    - Miscellaneous, 1918-1948; typescript, typescript carbon, printed material (Box 55)
    - About Anita Weschler sculpture, by AW, 1928-1941; 1942-1951; typescript carbon, clippings; 2 folders (Box 56)
  - Birthday book, 2 volumes (Box 56)
  - Book lists, phonograph record lists, 1922-1930 (Box 56)
  - Business cards (Box 56)
  - Calendars, 1955-1962; 8 volumes in 2 folders (Box 56)
  - Calendars, 1963-1972; 24 volumes in 4 folders (Box 57)
  - Calendars, oversize, 1964-1966; 1970; 4 items (Oversize 5)
  - Calendars, 1973-1978; 1984,; undated; 23 volumes in 5 folders (Box 58)
  - Calendars, oversize, 1985 (Oversize 5)
  - Diploma, Jun 1925; Anita Weschler, New York School of Fine & Applied Arts (Oversize 5)
  - Divorce papers, checkbook, nametags (Box 59)
  - Donations (Box 59)
  - Equipment and techniques brochures and articles, 1936-1959 (Box 59)
  - Exhibit identification tags (Box 59)
  - Exhibition schedules (Box 59)
  - Exhibitions and banquets, 3 folders (Box 59)
  - Federation of Modern Painters and Sculptors, 1940-1942; officers, finances, typescript press releases (Box 59)
  - The Fellowship of the Pennsylvania Academy of Fine Arts, 1936-1946 (Box 60)
  - Friends, articles re: (Box 60)
  - Gift enclosure cards (Box 60)
  - Guest book, exhibition of sculpture by A. Weschler at Hudson Park Library, 1938 (Box 60)
  - Invitations and events, 3 folders (Box 60)
  - Invitations and events, 3 folders (Box 61)
  - Knife (Oversize 4)
  - Letterheads (Box 61)
  - The Edward MacDowell Association, 1934-1953 (Box 61)
  - The MacDowell Colonists, New York Group, 1937; biographies and lists of members (Box 61)
  - Medical prescriptions (Box 61)
  - Membership cards, 1943-1959 (Box 61)
  - Membership and mailing lists (Box 61)
  - Membership and mailing lists (Box 62)
  - Memo books, 31 volumes in 4 folders (Box 62)
  - Memo books, 15 volumes in 3 folders (Box 63)
  - National Association of Woman Artists, 1945-1962 (Box 63)
  - News clippings, 4 folders (Box 63)
  - News clippings, 2 folders (Box 64)
  - Newsletters and business meetings, 2 folders (Box 64)
  - Photocopy of collage of news clippings by and about A. Weschler [1], 1939-1953 (Oversize 7)
  - Photocopy of collage of news clippings about A. Weschler [2], 1937-1953 (Oversize 7)
  - Photocopy of collage of news clippings about A. Weschler [3], 1937-1953 (Oversize 7)
  - Pique newsletters (Box 64)
  - Prints (Box 64)
  - Programs (Box 64)
  - Programs, 2 folders (Box 65)
  - Scrapbooks, 2 volumes (Oversize 8)
  - Sculptor's Guild, history, letterheads, checkbook, 1942 (Box 65)
  - Seminars and lectures (Box 65)
  - Smithsonian Gallery of Art competition, 1939-1940; competition to select architect (Box 65)
  - Telephone books, 2 volumes (Box 65)
  - Translucencies exhibit by A. Weschler, 1957; titles of works, invitations, lists (Box 65)
  - Travel
    - Denmark, 1959; guides, maps (Box 65)
    - England, 1950; guides, maps (Box 65)
    - Europe, 1949-1959; miscellaneous (Box 65)
    - France, 1948-1950; tour guides, receipts (Box 66)
    - Italy, 1951; guides, receipts (Box 66)
    - Mexico, Carribean, brochures, postcards (Box 66)
    - Norway, 1959; guides, maps, brochures (Box 66)
    - Ship's newspapers (Box 66)
    - Spain, guides (Box 66)
    - United States, 1926-1952; brochures, maps (Box 66)
    - time tables, 1948-1951 (Box 66)
    - Virgin Islands (Box 66)
  - United States Maritime Commission Competition (Box 66)
  - Weschler, Aldophus (Anita's uncle) (Box 66)
  - re: Weschler, J. Charles and Hulda Mayer, 1902; includes Hulda Mayer diary (Box 67)
  - Who's Who (Box 67)
  - Yaddo, brochure (Box 67)
  - Miscellaneous, 3 folders (Box 67)
  - Miscellaneous, 5 folders (Box 68)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 69)
  - Miscellaneous, sign/placard (Oversize 5)
- Photographs
  - Art works, 1929-1939; Anita Weschler, Paul Wescott and unidentified (Box 69)
  - Children and babies, unidentified (Box 69)
  - Family, 1903-1934 (Box 69)
  - Family, 3 generations including Anita Weschler (Oversize 5)
  - Friends, farm (Box 69)
  - Friends, identified, 1910-1935 (Box 69)
  - Houses, 1916 (Oversize 5)
  - Interiors, 1947 (Box 69)
  - Koestler, Elsa Weschler (Oversize 5)
  - Limon, Jose, 1940 (Oversize 5)
  - Models (Box 69)
  - People, unidentified, 1902-1933; 2 folders (Box 69)
  - Places, undated (Box 70)
  - Solomon, Herbert (Box 70)
  - Weschler, Adolphus (Box 70)
  - Weschler, Anita, 1918-1920; 1952,; undated (Box 70)
  - Weschler, Anita, 1938 (Oversize 5)
  - Weschler, Anita, undated; glass plate positive (Box 70)
  - Weschler, Anita and group, 1913 (Oversize 5)
  - Weschler, Anita, "A Time to Speak", 1947 (Oversize 5)
  - Weschler, Anita, works by (Box 70)
  - Weschler, J. Charles (Oversize 5)
  - Wilson, Woodrow (Box 70)
  - Young people, unidentified (Box 70)
  - Unidentified (Oversize 5)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 70)
  - Album, Hulda Eva Mayer, 1898; circa 1903; 2 albums, 1 folder (Box 70)